Daniel Harder

Junior Full Stack Developer

d.harder@gmx.at • +43 6603451339 • Innsbruck (AUT)

https://danio86.github.io/My-Resume/ • GitHub (linked in the webpage) • LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-harder-18713223a

Executive Summary

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute in progress. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python. Through my work as a coach and science teacher and through the relevant studies I have over 10 years of experience in dealing with people, customers and colleagues. I was able to motivate others and myself to achieve goals efficiently and complete projects. I am a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

Education

August 2022–August 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland -

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

September 2014–June 2020 Mag. Rer. Nat. (Magister rerum naturalium) – MSc (Master of Science)

Vienna Main University, AUT

Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize

In progress: React

Version Control: Git, Github

Portfolio projects

1. Every day-selector - Movie, Series and Food Selector for people who don't want to think about what they want to eat, drink, or watch on TV today.

Technologies Used – Python. - https://everyday-selector.herokuapp.com

2. Snake-2001- Snake game with three levels.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS with, JavaScript. GitHub - https://danio86.github.io/Snake-2001/

3. Coach-Finder - Web site where users can find and connect coaches for any sport. This can be used for groups or for individuals.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS. GitHub - https://danio86.github.io/coach-finder

Work Experience

September 2020–Present

High School Teacher of Science, Geography and Economics

BFI, Vienna, AUT

- I have taught biology, chemistry, physics, geography and economics to teenagers and adults.
- I taught about sustainable environmental protection
- In the corona era, a lot of work was done online and with different software.
- Numerous groups were organized and guided.
- We worked with many colleagues in the team.

April 2008–September 2020

Self-employed personal trainer

Fitness clubs: Get Up – Fitness, Fitness Club Activity, Holmes Place and private Vienna and Lower Austria

- I have worked with adults on their athletic/physical goals.
- Training and nutrition plans were developed theoretically and implemented in practice.
- Customer contacts were built up and maintained.
- It was worked together in different fitness clubs in teams to satisfy the customers and to develop the fitness club.
- Organizational office work was carried out.

October 2010–March 2020

Self-employed Masseur and Sports Masseur

Privat, Vienna, AUT

- I have built up and maintained a customer base.
- I have worked with amateur and competitive athletes to increase their performance.

Certifications

- FreeCodeCamp Scientific Computing with Python (300 hours)
- FreeCodeCamp Data Analysis with Python (300 hours)

Interests/Additional Information

- Coding small Projects for fun and friends
- I do sports activities in nature: Climbing, skiing, diving (advanced, open water diver), hiking
- I travel the world backpacking or road tripping
- Fluent German, Fluent English